bmc-switzerland.com 2019-12-09

# Privacy and Cookie Policy

## 1. General Information

The protection and security of personal data is a top priority for BMC Switzerland AG, Sportstrasse 49, 2540 Grenchen (hereinafter " **BMC** "). We place great value on openness and transparency. This Data Protection Policy will provide you with information on the nature, scope, and purpose of personal data processed by us. In addition, it contains information concerning your rights.

Personal data is information that relates to an identified or identifiable individual ("data subject"). "Processing" means any process, performed with or without the aid of automated processes, in connection with personal data, such as collection, recording, storage, adaptation or alteration, retrieval, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination or otherwise making available, or erasure.

## 2. Name and address of the responsible person

The responsible person is defined as the natural or legal person that determines the purposes and means of processing personal data.  
Presently responsible is:

**BMC Switzerland AG  
** Sportstrasse 49  
2540 Grenchen  
Switzerland  
Phone.: +41 79 1719 94 91  
E-mail: privacy@bmc-switzerland.com  
Website: www.bmc-switzerland.com

## 3. Name and address of the Data Protection Officer

Any person who is a data subject of our data processing can contact our data protection officer directly in case of a question or a request regarding data protection. This is:

Armin Amsler  
c/o BMC Switzerland AG  
Sportstrasse 49  
2540 Grenchen  
Switzerland  
Phone.: +41 32 654 14 54  
E-mail: privacy@bmc-switzerland.com

## 4. Categories of personal data

BMC can process the following categories of personal data. In doing so, BMC does not process any more personal data than is necessary.  
BMC processes customer data. By this we mean, in particular: 

  * Master and inventory data (e.g. name, address, date of birth, telephone number, gender, size, weight, age, contract number and duration, information concerning completed transactions, bank details)
  * Marketing data (e.g. requirements, wishes, preferences, information on participation in surveys, contests and events)
  * Technical data (e.g. internal and external identifiers, business numbers, IP addresses, records of accesses or amendments, e-mail addresses)
  * Usage data of plugins from social networks like Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, YouTube, etc. (See also point 16 below). These usage data form the basis of anonymized statistical evaluations in order to identify trends which BMC can use to improve our offers accordingly.

BMC may also collect information from third parties to identify potential customers who may be interested in bicycles or bicycle accessories.

BMC processes supplier data. By this we mean, in particular:

  * Master and inventory data (e.g. name, address, date of birth, telephone number, contract number and duration, information concerning completed transactions, bank details)
  * Marketing data (e.g. requirements, wishes, preferences)
  * Technical data (e.g. internal and external identifiers, business numbers, IP addresses, records of accesses or amendments, e-mail addresses)

## 5. Duration of storage

The duration of storage of personal data is determined by statutory retention obligations (depending on the applicable legal basis, these are five, ten, or more years), or by the purpose of the data processing concerned.

## 6. Purpose of the Data Processing

BMC may process the personal data described in point 4 for the execution of its own services as well as for its own or legally intended purposes. This includes in particular the implementation and execution of contracts, planning and product development, marketing, market research, comprehensive support, advice and information on the provision of services, preparation and delivery of tailored services, legal or regulatory informing or reporting obligations to courts and authorities, and compliance with official regulations.

## 7. Legal basis for data processing

Data processing is lawful, insofar as the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or in order to take steps at the request of the data subject prior to entering into a contract. This is the case, for example, for processing operations that are necessary for the supply of goods or the provision of other services or considerations. The same applies to such processing operations as are required for the implementation of precontractual measures in cases of questions about our products or services.

In addition, data processing is lawful if the data subject has given their consent to the processing or if the processing is necessary for the fulfillment of a legal obligation on the part of BMC. Further, data processing is lawful if it is necessary to protect the legitimate interests of BMC or a third party, which may be the case, for example, if the data subject is a customer of BMC. In addition, data processing is lawful if the vital interests of a natural person are to be protected or if the processing is necessary for the performance of a task which is in the public interest.

## 8. Data security

Your personal data provided to us will be secured by taking technical and organizational security measures in such a way that they are inaccessible to unauthorized third parties. These security measures are continually adapted and improved as new technology develops.

## 9. Transfer of personal data

BMC will not sell, disclose, or otherwise distribute your personal information to third parties except as described in this data protection policy. We may share your personal information with other BMC global affiliates if they agree to treat the data in accordance with this data protection policy. 

Your personal data may also be passed on to third parties (e.g. business partners of BMC) who act for us or on our behalf, in order for them to further process the data for the purpose/purposes for which the data were originally collected, or for other legally permissible purposes. These third parties have contractually committed to use personal data for the agreed purposes only, not to sell to other parties, and not to disclose to other parties, unless this is legally required, permitted by us or described in this data protection policy. Personal data can be transferred to hosting companies and web agencies, which support BMC in the design, development, analysis, and operation of the website. These companies use the personal data only to perform the described work and are obligated to treat the data confidentially.

Personal data may also be disclosed to third parties if we are required to do so by law, by injunction or by official regulations, or in support of criminal or legal investigations, or other legal investigations or proceedings in Switzerland or abroad.

## 10. Rights of the data subject 

You can ask BMC for information about whether or not personal data is processed about you. If this is the case, we will inform you of the personal data held about you in our database, including the information available on the origin of the data, the purpose and, where applicable, the legal basis for processing and the categories of processed personal data, those involved in the collection and the data recipient. You further have the right to rectification, a right to deletion of personal data (right to be forgotten), a right to limitation of processing, a right to data transferability, and the right to revoke a data protection consent.

All requests for information and other concerns regarding data protection will be handled by our data protection officer (cf. point 3).

## 11. Data logging when visiting this website 

When you visit the BMC website, the web server automatically records log files that cannot be assigned to any particular person. These data include, for example, the browser type and version, operating system used, referrer URL (previously visited page), IP address of the requesting computer, access date and time of the server request, and the client's file request (file name and URL). These data are collected solely for statistical analysis purposes. We will not disclose these data to third parties for commercial or noncommercial purposes.

## 12. Bike registration

When you register your BMC bike on our website, we will use your information as follows:

BMC uses the data to provide you with the best possible warranty service, or to meet your contact requirements. There will be no further use of your personal data. Your personal data will not be transmitted to third parties, and no use of your data for advertising purposes will take place unless you have expressly consented to it.

By registering, you agree that your information will be stored and used for market research purposes.

## 13. Newsletter

You have the option of subscribing to our newsletter via our website. For this we need your e-mail address and your declaration that you agree to receive the newsletter. To provide you with targeted information, we also collect and process voluntarily provided information about areas of interest. Your information may be stored and used for market research and advertising purposes.

You can cancel your subscription to the newsletter at any time. Please send your cancellation to the following e-mail address: info@bmc-switzerland.com. We will immediately delete your data in connection with sending the newsletter.

## 14. Cookies

Our website uses "session cookies" to facilitate your use of our website. These are small text files stored on your hard drive only for the duration of your visit to our website and, depending on the setting of the browser program, deleted when you exit the browser. These cookies do not retrieve information stored on your hard drive, nor do they interfere with your PC or files. Most browsers are automatically set to accept cookies. You can, however, deactivate the storage of cookies or set your browser to notify you when cookies are sent.

## 15. Notice: Google Analytics

The BMC website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service of Google Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses "cookies". These are text files that are stored on your computer and which enable an analysis of your use of the website. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) is transmitted to a Google server in the U.S. and stored there. Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity for its operators and to provide other services related to website activity and internet usage. Google will also transmit this information to third parties, insofar as this is required by law or if third parties process this data on behalf of Google. Google will not under any circumstances associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may block the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. However, please be advised that if you opt out of using cookies, you may not be able to use all the features of this website to their fullest extent. By using this website, you agree that the data that Google collects about you may be processed as described above and for the purpose described above. Furthermore, you can prevent the collection of data generated by the cookie and related to your usage of the website (including your IP address) and the processing of the data by Google by downloading and installing the browser plugin available via the following link:

[http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de].

## 16. Use of Social Network Plugins

There are social networking functions from various social networking sites (Facebook, Twitter, Google+, YouTube, Instagram, etc.) embedded in the BMC website. These functions are provided by the respective network providers in the form of plugins.

When using the BMC website, the user's browser creates a direct connection with the computers of the respective network provider to initiate the social plugins. The network providers receive information via the plugin activation that the user is on the BMC website. If the user is logged on to the network provider with a personal account at the same time, the network provider can assign the visit to the corresponding user profile. If in addition the user interacts directly with the plugins, the relevant information and possible further information (e.g. IP address, browser type, retrieved domains, visited pages, mobile phone providers, device and application IDs, etc.) may be transmitted directly to the network provider and stored there.

Please note that, as the operator of this website, BMC has no knowledge of the content of the data transmitted or of how each network provider uses this data. Due to continuous updating of the data protection policies of the various network providers, the links to the current regulations of the various network providers are listed here:

  * Facebook Data Use Policy
  * Twitter Privacy Policy
  * Google+ - Google Privacy Policy
  * YouTube - Google Privacy Policy
  * Instagram Privacy Policy
  * Disqus Privacy Policy
  * AddThis Privacy Policy

## 17. Data protection for applications and application procedures

The person responsible for processing collects and processes the personal data of applicants for the purpose of processing the application procedure. The processing can also be done electronically. This is particularly the case when an applicant transmits corresponding application documents to the responsible person by electronic means, for example by e-mail. If the responsible person concludes an employment contract with an applicant, the transferred data will be stored for the purpose of processing the employment relationship, in compliance with the legal regulations. If the responsible person does not conclude an employment contract with the applicant, the application documents are automatically deleted six months after the notification of the rejection decision, provided that the deletion is not contrary to other legitimate interests of the responsible person.

## 18. Updating and Modification of this Data Protection Policy

Parts of this data protection policy may be modified or updated by us without prior notice to you. Please check the data protection policy each time you visit our website, to ensure you are up to date on any changes or updates. Last updated: May 2018
